Debra J. Slater, CLA

Certified Legal Assistant

Objective

To bring substantial, well-rounded experience as a legal support professional; working independently and as part of a team, focusing on providing top-notch client service. To continue learning and taking on new challenges in an ever-changing field and world.

Experience

Feb. 2008-Present

Bodyfelt Mount LLP

Portland, OR

Legal Assistant

 Secretarial and paralegal support for senior partner and associate emphasizing insurance defense, insurance coverage, environmental and general business litigation in state, federal, and bankruptcy courts in Oregon and Washington. Conventional and electronic filing (ECF), discovery and file organization; scheduling, docketing case deadlines. Drafting and editing pleadings and correspondence. Familiar with court rules and procedures. Assist with trial, hearing and deposition preparation.

Nov. 2005-Feb. 2008

Black Helterline LLP

Portland, OR

Legal Assistant

• Multi-level support for senior partner and associate emphasizing litigation, general business, intellectual property, technology, debtor-creditor, construction and real estate. Electronic filing, calendaring, for matters in state, federal and bankruptcy courts in Oregon, Washington, other states (*pro hac vice*), and US Trademark matters. Drafted pleadings, documents and correspondence, researched rules and procedures; assisted in trial, deposition and hearing preparation.

Mar. 2004-Nov. 2005

Garvey Schubert Barer

Portland, OR

Legal Assistant

- Supported two owners emphasizing litigation and general business, corporate and securities matters.
- Drafted documents and correspondence, prepared discovery documents and other paralegal duties.

Feb. 2003-Mar. 2004

Hoffman Hart & Wagner LLP

Portland, OR

Legal Assistant/Secretary

• Litigation – primarily insurance defense, construction defect and medical malpractice.

Jan. 1997-Feb. 2003

Harrang Long Gary Rudnick PC

Eugene, OR

Paralegal and Legal Assistant/Secretary

- Complex litigation, public entity representation, employment and general business litigation in state and federal trial and appellate courts. General employment law, business/corporate and real estate.
- Paralegal duties including drafting pleadings, motions, discovery requests and responses; proofreading and cite-checking briefs; document and electronic database set-up and management; deposition preparation and summaries; trial preparation.
- Managed large and small cases, trained and supervised project assistant in Summation.
- Served on Training & Development Committee; participated in technology-related firm projects.

Feb. 1994-Sept. 1996

Mersereau & Shannon LLP

Portland, OR

Legal Secretary/Assistant

• Supported two litigators in small firm focusing in public entity representation, municipal finance, employment law, school law, and business litigation, in state and federal trial and appellate courts and LUBA. (Rehired by former partners of Rankin VavRosky firm, see below.)

Mar. 1993-Feb. 1994

Davis Wright Tremaine LLP

Portland, OR

Legal Secretary

• Supported three attorneys focusing in real estate, municipal finance and estate planning, including paralegal duties related to municipal finance.

July 1989-Jan. 1993

Schulte, Anderson, Downes & Aronson, P.C.

Portland, OR

Legal Secretary

• Supported senior shareholder emphasizing real estate and general business, including drafting documents for real estate and commercial loan transactions and workouts, trust deed and judicial foreclosures, FED, collections, general business, corporate organization and maintenance.

June 1988–July 1989 Rankin VavRosky Doherty MacColl & Mersereau

Portland, OR

Legal Secretary/Assistant

 Secretarial and paralegal support in municipal finance, corporate organization and maintenance, including drafting documents.

Nov. 1985-Dec. 1987

Hershner, Hunter, Andrews, Neill & Smith, LLP

Eugene, OR

Legal Secretary

• Supported senior partner focusing in real estate and business transactions, drafted standard documents; also assisted on creditors rights and bankruptcy matters, trust deed foreclosures and litigation.

Education

Sept. 2003-June 2011

Linfield College, Department of Continuing Education

Portland, OR

- Part-time student earning BS degree in Social & Behavioral Sciences (senior)
- Completed Business Law I, Summer 2004 (A); International Business Law, Spring 2005 (A)

Jan. 1985–Sept. 1985 University of Oregon

Eugene, OR

• General undergraduate studies

Skills

- Type 100 WPM
- Proficient in MS Office 2010 and earlier; Internet research skills
- Excellent spelling, grammar, composition, proofreading and editing
- Summation experience and training since 1999 (more recent training 2007 and 2010)
- Experience with timekeeping and document management programs
- LEXIS and Westlaw
- Oregon Notary Public

Certification

Certified Legal Assistant / Certified Paralegal since January 2000 (designation of National Association of Legal Assistants)

Memberships

National Association of Legal Assistants Pacific Northwest Paralegal Association

Interests

Family, nature and wildlife, photography, birding, art, running and fitness, lifetime learning.